A Guide to the Boothe Family Papers, 1787-1879
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Boothe Family Papers, 1787-1879
Library of Virginia
35532
.675 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary Boothe Healey, 28 August 1997 and 23 September 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Boothe family were prominent residents of Nansemond County, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
This accession consists of three series of Boothe family papers. They document the legal activities, as well as financial actions and fiduciary responsibilities of Nathaniel Boothe and his son, Joseph Boothe, of Nansemond County, Virginia. Included are a variety of fiscal accounts with allied families. There is a limited amount of correspondence, as well as deeds, a will, and numerous notes, bills, accounts, and tax records.
The papers were arranged chronologically by the donor and her mother and calendars of each series of items were prepared. The original order has been maintained as much as possible, annotations were made on the donor created finding aid to indicate any changes. The finding aids are filed at the front of each series. Series 1 and 2 comprise Acc.35485 and Series 3 is Acc.35532. The two accessions are filed together under the earlier accession. A detailed itemized listing of the papers is filed within each box.
Arrangement
Arranged into three series: Series 1 (1787-1879), Series 2 (1824-1850), Series 3 (1850-1867) and then chronologically by year therein.
Contents List
- Series I, 1787-1879
  - Papers, 1787-1819 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1820-1827 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1830-1835 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1836-1839 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1840-1844 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1845-1849 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1850-1854 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1855-1859 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Papers, 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Papers, 1870-1879, nd (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Papers, 1834-1836 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II, 1824-1850
  - Papers, 1824-1829 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Papers, 1830-1833 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Papers, 1834-1835 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Papers, 1836-1837 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Papers, 1838-1840 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Papers, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1841-1842 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1843-1850 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series III, 1850-1867
  - Papers, nd (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1851-1852 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1853-1854 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Papers, 1855-1856 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Papers, 1857-1859 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Papers, 1860-1867 (Box 2, Folder 10)